blogtalkradio.com 2015-12-25

# Blogtalkradio Terms of Use and Privacy Policy

## Terms of Use

### Effective Date: March 26th, 2015

##### 1\. Your Agreement With BTR

These terms make up an agreement between BlogTalkRadio, Inc., any individuals or companies affiliated with or which succeed it (“BTR”), and you. These Terms apply to your use of the BTR website, service applications, products and content provided by BTR (the “BTR Services”), globally, in existence now or in the future. You acknowledge that prior to using the BTR Services you have read these Terms carefully and agree to be bound by them. These Terms control your use of the BTR Services even if they are inconsistent with other information you have read. Please don’t use BTR Services if you don’t agree with these Terms (as well as all other policies and rules that BTR has posted on its website or provided to you).

You further acknowledge that these Terms may be amended. If this occurs, BTR will give you reasonable advance notice on the BTR website so that you can review the amendments and terminate your account within the notice period if you don’t agree to them. If you don’t terminate your account by the time the amendments go into effect, your continued use of the BTR Services will be subject to the amended Terms. 

You also acknowledge that if you are using the BTR Services, you are not a child (in other words, you are over the age of 13) and agree that your use of the BTR Services will not violate any law or regulation. If you are a child below the age of 13, consider yourself lucky because you can stop reading now (since BTR does not allow you to use BTR Services and will terminate your profile and registration when it discovers that you are too young to be here). BTR will also terminate the profile and services of anyone who violates these Terms. 

##### In brief...

By using BlogTalkRadio.com you agree to the terms below.

##### 2\. Your Account with BTR

Before using BTR Services, you will need to register with BTR and give us some basic background information. Your registration constitutes an acknowledgement that you will use the BTR Services for your own personal purposes. If you want to use the BTR Services for commercial purposes, you will have to sign up for our Revenue Engine (which provides a very easy way to make money on your podcasts distributed using the BTR platform). You also agree that you will not copy or distribute the BTR Services in any medium unless we know about it and you use our technology to do so. 

We hope that you are interested in using our services because you like the BTR platform. That being said, you agree not to alter or change the BTR Services other than as needed to make them work for you. Your registration with BTR and use of the BTR Services allows us to include your user name and descriptions of Your Content (as defined below) in a directory or promotions on the BTR website, and to display visual material simultaneously with the delivery of Your Content if it is transmitted audibly. 

As a company committed to improving the world of podcasting, we strive to create innovations that make a difference in our users’ lives and have gone to great lengths to deliver them. If you are in a business similar to BTR’s, please do not register for the BTR Services. By registering with us or continuing to use the BTR Services, you acknowledge that you are not a contractor, or an affiliate, employee or owner of a podcast hosting, streaming, syndication, measurement, or monetization service provider. You also acknowledge and agree that you will not disclose information to other parties about BTR’s business processes and technologies, and that you will not attempt to recreate BTR’s business processes and technologies for the purpose of engaging in or offering a service similar to BTR’s.

##### In brief...

You need to create your own account to use BlogTalkRadio.com and you promise not to try to break BlogTalkRadio.com or extract information other than through sanctioned channels. 

##### 3\. Basic BTR Services are Free!

Believe it or not, unless you are using BTR’s premium services, your non-commercial use of the basic BTR Services is free. If we ever decide to charge you in the future for basic BTR Services, we will let you know ahead of time. If you are interested in using BTR’s premium services for a fee, please click here.

##### In brief...

Most basic services are free. Really.

##### 4\. Creation and Transmission of Podcasts

BTR enables you to set up a host channel and create audio webcasts and/or podcasts, and metadata and supporting content, including audio files, video files, text and images (collectively, “Your Content”), which are transmitted using BTR’s audio webcasting, hosting and syndication platform. BTR continually works to improve the technology used to deliver the BTR Services, and will notify you of changes to the way you create and submit Your Content by posting them on the BTR website.

##### In brief...

The BlogTalkRadio platform helps you with all the technical aspects of hosting managing and distributing your podcasts. We will keep improving our services for you.

##### 5\. Syndication

BTR facilitates the syndication of its users’ podcasts by creating RSS Feeds via Atom/RSS or other similar protocols (the “BTR RSS Feeds”). Once you set up a BTR account, BTR will create a BTR RSS Feed of Your Content that you may use as a means to syndicate Your Content to channels like iTunes, Stitcher, Podcast App, Overcast and many others. We will also provide a means for you to embed Your Content on your website via an embeddable widget.

In order to simplify and unify the process of tracking consumption of Your Content across multiple platforms, you agree to use the BTR RSS Feed as the primary syndication feed for Your Content to other platforms, and to use the provided embeddable BTR player as a means to embed Your Content on your website/blogs (where it is possible to embed from a technical or policy perspective). 

Your cooperation with this provision ensures that our systems can obtain a more complete view of the listening activity with respect to Your Content and allows us to effectively market your show to potential sponsors and advertisers.

##### In brief...

You agree to use the RSS feed from BlogTalkRadio to distribute your podcast as broadly as you like. This also helps us more accurately measure your listenership.

##### 6\. BTR’s License

As sole owner of Your Content, you grant us the right to use it. In other words, you grant BTR (and any of its affiliated companies, licensees or assignees) a perpetual, royalty-free, non-exclusive right and license on a world-wide basis to transmit, perform and publicly display digitally, distribute and syndicate Your Content for all purposes, to the extent permitted by law. This will allow BTR to transmit, on a world-wide basis, and permit its end users (and other internet website operators and their end users) to access Your Content on the BTR website and applications, affiliated services and syndication channels. Pay close attention because this is important: **except for the rights expressly granted in this paragraph, BTR does not gain any further interest in or right to use Your Content, all of which shall remain solely with you.**

##### In brief...

**The content of your webcasts is always 100% owned by you** , but BlogTalkRadio has permission to use the content you publish here.

##### 7\. Content of Podcasts

By using the BTR Services, you acknowledge and agree that with respect to Your Content created or uploaded to the BTR platform: 

  1. You own the content or have the right to use it. In other words, you either created Your Content yourself or are legally entitled to use it publicly. This means that if you don’t own Your Content, you have obtained all licenses to use it that may be required under the Digital Millennium Copyright Act, United States Copyright Law, and any other applicable copyright laws, and your use of the content doesn’t conflict with any other licenses that you may have granted. This also means that you have the written permission of any identifiable person included in Your Content to use his or her name or likeness, and that you either own or control all rights to any musical or sound recording that you use. If for some reason BTR asks to see it, you agree to provide BTR with all documents proving that you own or have the right to use the content in Your Content; 
  2. You will be provided with BTR software. BTR will give you access to all software required to use the BTR Services upon your acceptance of these Terms and log-in to the BTR website, and your use of the software will be subject to these Terms;
  3. BTR may provide you with archive space to store and host Your Content. You may be provided with free storage space for archiving Your Content and associated metadata, depending on BTR’s then-existing storage policies as listed on the BTR website. If BTR provides you with storage space for Your Content, you acknowledge that BTR may decide to charge at some point for this storage or cancel the storage and hosting altogether; 
  4. You are responsible for and assume all risks associated with Your Content. You agree to take responsibility for Your Content, whether contributed by you or under your authority, including the content that is contributed by any guest or contributor. You agree to warn listeners of any explicit content in Your Content, including profanity or subject matter that might not be suitable for all ages. 
  5. You agree to make sure that Your Content is truthful, bug-free and doesn’t violate anyone’s rights. You agree that Your Audio Content will not contain any material that: 
    * is obscene, indecent, offensive, libelous, hateful, racially or ethnically offensive, defamatory, unreasonably violent, threatening, intimidating, harassing, or features any illegal or pornographic content (including child pornography);
    * is false or makes untrue statements that could damage anyone, including your listeners; 
    * contains any viruses, Trojan horses, worms, or other disabling devices or harmful things intended to damage, detrimentally interfere with, or secretly intercept or copy any system, data or personal information;
    * advocates or encourages any illegal or potentially illegal activity, including pyramid schemes;
    * is not spam, is not machine- or randomly-generated, and does not contain unethical or unwanted commercial content designed to drive traffic to third party sites or boost the search engine rankings of third party sites, or to further unlawful acts (such as phishing) or mislead recipients as to the source of the material (such as spoofing);
    * is getting advertised via unwanted electronic messages such as spam links on newsgroups, email lists, other blogs and web sites, and similar unsolicited, or machine generated traffic promotion methods;
    * is not presented in a manner that misleads your readers into thinking that you are another person or company; and
    * infringes on anyone’s intellectual property or other legal rights;
    * violates anyone’s privacy, or impersonates another person;
    * gives rise to any civil liability or violates the law; or
    * violates the acceptable use policies of any networks, machines, or services that are accessed through the BTR website. 
  6. BTR has the right to refuse to transmit any portion of Your Content that is prohibited by these Terms. BTR will be paying attention to Your Content to make sure you abide by these Terms. If BTR deems Your Content to be in violation of these Terms or finds it objectionable for any reason, we will not transmit Your Content.
  7. BTR’s owned content is off limits. Except for Your Content, BTR owns or licenses from third parties the text, software, graphics, photos, sounds, videos, interactive features, and all related trademarks, service marks and logos on the BTR website. This content is provided to you AS IS for your information and personal use only, and you may not copy or reproduce it in any way without BTR’s prior written consent. BTR (and any other owners of this content) reserve all rights not expressly granted in this content and the BTR website. 

##### In brief...

Don't publish content owned by others unless you have written permission. Also no plagiarism, spam, viruses, porn or any content that hurts listeners please.

##### 8\. Content Access Rules

BTR has worked for years to develop a unique and useful platform, and we are protective of it. We ask that your use of the BTR Services take this into account. You may not use any “deep-link”, “page-scrape”, “robot”, “spider” or other automatic device, program, algorithm or methodology, or any similar or equivalent manual process, to access, acquire, copy or monitor any portion of the BTR website or its content except via BTR RSS Feeds and application programming interfaces. This rule does not apply to you if you are operating a search engine that is an exposed public web service designed solely to help discover and direct users to the BTR website and the content created by our creator community.

When downloading audio content from the BTR website or BTR RSS Feeds, you may not cache the BTR RSS Feeds or linked audio content in a way that would obscure the actual download activity of users within your application. You are also prohibited from in any way reproducing or circumventing the navigational structure or presentation of the BTR website or any of its content. You acknowledge and agree not to obtain (or attempt to obtain) any materials, documents or information from the BTR website through any means not purposely made available by BTR.

##### In brief...

Please use the platform in the way it is intended to be used.

##### 9\. Monetization and Advertising

By using the BTR Services, you agree not to directly monetize Your Content via third party ad networks, agencies or business agreements. This restriction does not limit indirect monetization of Your Content, or services you offer outside of Your Content or your own promotions for those services. You may also include in Your Content advertising or sponsored messages/segments, but to do so you will need to either (i) notify BTR and receive written clearance or (ii) enroll in BTR’s Revenue Engine and use BTR’s ad systems in compliance with the advertisement/sponsorship policies of the BTR Revenue Engine. In fact, please note that if it is your intent to monetize Your Content, jumping aboard the BTR Revenue Engine is truly the best way to go, since it will allow BTR to work to maximize your potential earnings and provide an efficient way to remit to you the lion’s share of net revenues generated by Your Content. (See Revenue Engine section below).

By using the BTR Services, you are granting, and acknowledge that BTR in its sole discretion has, the right to serve banner, audio and video advertisements, including live reads, promotions, or other sponsored segments in connection with Your Content. You also acknowledge and agree that BTR may earn revenues associated with Your Content (including advertising fees, commissions, syndication fees and the like). It is our intent to work with the best advertisers and sponsors that do not compromise your editorial integrity, are not distasteful, and that do not interfere with the listening experience of Your Content. If you see or hear objectionable ads around or within Your Content, please email badads@blogtalkradio.com and our ad operations team will be happy to review these cases.

##### In brief...

You agree to allow BlogTalkRadio help you make money for you from your content and give the lion’s share of revenues to you. If you are already monetizing your content we won’t get in the way of those relationships.

##### 10\. Revenue Engine

To begin directly monetizing your content, and to enable BTR to remit to you your share of the revenues earned in connection with Your Content, your enrollment in the BTR Revenue Engine is required. Admittedly, these revenues might be very small as you ramp up your audiences, but they have the potential to grow! The BTR Revenue Engine assists BTR hosts by locating sponsors and advertisers for their BTR channel and content, and executing those sponsorships and advertising with BTR’s proprietary technologies. The full benefits of the BTR Revenue Engine are explained here. 

In a nutshell, the primary benefit of the Revenue Engine program is that it can allow you to receive the majority share of aggregate revenues earned against Your Content (less third party commissions and fees). BTR retains only a small share of these revenues, which allows us to take on the operational tasks of searching for advertisers and sponsors on your behalf, executing monetization instruments against Your Content using our proprietary technologies, and working behind the scenes to maximize your earning potential. This program frees up your time for more important things like focusing on your content and growing your listenership.

If you already have pre-existing long-term sponsorship arrangements generating sufficient revenues, please let our revenue team know via revengine@blogtalkradio.com. We do not want to jeopardize or limit these pre-existing relationships, and will work with you to ensure that you can fulfill your obligations to your pre-existing sponsors within our platform without limiting your total earning potential.

##### In brief...

You need to sign up with the Revenue Engine if you want to make money from your BlogTalkRadio content.

##### 11\. Contacting Us 

If you need to write to us, use this address: BlogTalkRadio, Inc., 1072 Madison Ave, Lakewood, NJ 08701. 

##### 12\. Responsible Disclosures

If you need to report unlawful conduct, including copyright or intellectual property infringement, please email us at [ legal@BlogTalkRadio.com](mailto:legal@BlogTalkRadio.com).

. 

##### 13\. Lawyer Stuff (which must be read CAREFULLY) 

**We apologize profusely for what comes next, which is written in legalese (sometimes in ALL CAPS) that has survived the tests of time and trial. Please read this stuff carefully, since it is actually important:**

**Termination:** If you don’t abide by these Terms, or if BTR is unable to verify the information you provide to it when you register, BTR may terminate your use of the BTR Services or access to the BTR website immediately without prior notice. 

**Proprietary Information and Confidentiality:** You acknowledge and agree that BTR or its licensees are the sole owners of the services, operations, software, products, business methods and processes, tools, sales information, algorithms, search engines, search indices, and any advertisement insertion software used in connection with the BTR website (the “BTR Business Products”), including, without limitation, all intellectual property rights therein, and that you will not acquire any rights in the BTR Business Products except as expressly set forth in these Terms. You retain ownership of all of your trademarks, trade names, logos and other intellectual property contained in Your Content, and BTR shall not acquire any rights therein.

Information that BTR or you obtain about the other in connection with the BTR Services, including, without limitation, information concerning operations, processes, business methods, tools, software, algorithms, search engines, search indices, products, services, policies, sales information and other such information deemed privileged in the judgment of the respective party, is to remain confidential and proprietary to the party which it concerns, except to the extent necessary for either party to disclose matters concerning the BTR Services to the other. 

**Choice of Law/Arbitration:** The interpretation and enforcement of these Terms and the resulting agreement between you and BTR shall be governed by the laws of the State of New York, without regard to its conflicts of laws principles. You and BTR agree that any and all disputes arising out of or related to these Terms and our agreement shall be resolved solely through binding arbitration pursuant to the provisions of this paragraph 13 and the then-current rules of the American Arbitration Association (to the extent not inconsistent with this paragraph). Any arbitration arising out of or related to these Terms or our agreement shall be held in the Borough of Manhattan in the City and State of New York, before one independent arbitrator agreed upon by both parties. Any arbitration will be final and binding, and the arbitrator's order will be entered and enforceable in any court of competent jurisdiction. The arbitrator will be chosen within thirty (30) days of the date that any issue is submitted to arbitration (the "Submission Date"), discovery (if any) will be completed within sixty (60) days after the Submission Date, the arbitration hearing will occur within ninety (90) days after the Submission Date, and the arbitrator must render his or her decision, in writing, within thirty (30) days after the conclusion of the arbitration hearing. 

**Remedy:** Your sole remedy for any breach by BTR of these Terms or our agreement shall be the commencement of an arbitration proceeding for money damages, if any. In no event shall you be entitled to injunctive or other equitable relief based on any act or omission of BTR, or any breach of these Terms or by BTR. 

**Entire Agreement:** These Terms and our agreement in accordance therewith constitute the entire understanding of the parties with respect to the subject matter hereof. There are no understandings, agreements, conditions or representations, oral or written, express or implied, with reference to the subject matter hereof, that are not merged herein, expressly referenced herein, or superseded hereby. 

Independent Contractor/No Employment Relationship: Nothing contained in these Terms or our agreement shall be construed as creating any agency, partnership, joint venture or other form of joint enterprise between you and BTR. You further agree that you are not an employee of BTR and that no employer-employee relationship of any kind whatsoever exists between you and BTR. 

**Severability:** These Terms and the provisions of our agreement are independent of each other and the invalidity of any term, provision or a portion thereof shall not affect the validity or enforceability of any other term or provision. In the event that any particular term or provision is found to be invalid or unenforceable, such term or provision shall be deemed to have been replaced with a valid and enforceable term or provision that approximates as closely as possible the intent of the parties as reflected in the original term or provision. 

**No Waiver:** Any delay or failure on the part of BTR to enforce any rights hereunder to which it may be entitled shall not be construed as a waiver of the right and privilege to do so at any subsequent time. 

**Indemnification:** You indemnify and hold harmless BTR, and the officers, directors, employees, partners, principals, agents and representatives of BTR, from, against and in respect of any and all demands, claims, actions, causes of action, liabilities, losses and expenses, including reasonable attorneys' fees, arising out of or relating to (a) your participation in or use of the BTR website or any of the websites, facilities, software, transmission capabilities, or services of BTR; (b) any breach by you of any of these Terms, or of any covenant, representation or warranty made by you in our agreement; (c) any claims that Your Content or other use of the BTR website or BTR Services violates the intellectual property rights of any third parties, defames any third parties, constitutes impermissible hate speech or otherwise violates any rights of free speech or any other rights of any third parties; and (d) any portion of Your Content created or hosted by you or under your authority, including the content that you generate as well as any content contributed in any manner by any guest or caller. This defense and indemnification obligation will survive any termination of our agreement and your use of the BTR website or the BTR Services.

**Survival:** All provisions which must survive in order to give effect to their meaning shall survive any expiration or earlier termination of our agreement, including, without limitation all of your representations, warranties and indemnification obligations.

##### In brief...

Stuff our lawyers made us include to protect you and to protect BTR. These sections detail your rights and our rights in terms of content, products, remedies and liabilities.

**Disclaimer of Warranties; Limitation of Liability:**

THE BTR SERVICES, BTR RSS FEEDS, INFORMATION, CONTENT, AUDIO TRANSMISSIONS OR OTHER DATA OF ANY KIND OR NATURE MADE AVAILABLE AT THE BTR WEBSITE (COLLECTIVELY, "INFORMATION") ARE PROVIDED "AS IS", AND ALL REPRESENTATIONS AND WARRANTIES, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED ARE DISCLAIMED, INCLUDING WITHOUT LIMITATION, WARRANTIES OF TITLE, NON-INFRINGEMENT, MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. BTR MAKES NO WARRANTY, REPRESENTATION OR GUARANTY AS TO THE CONTENT, SEQUENCE, ACCURACY, TIMELINESS OR COMPLETENESS OF THE BTR WEBSITE OR THE INFORMATION OR THAT THE INFORMATION MAY BE RELIED UPON FOR ANY REASON. BTR MAKES NO WARRANTY, REPRESENTATION OR GUARANTY THAT USE OF THE BTR WEBSITE, BTR RSS REEDS, BTR SERVICES OR THE INFORMATION WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED, SECURE, VIRUS-FREE OR ERROR-FREE OR THAT ANY DEFECTS CAN BE CORRECTED. YOU SPECIFICALLY ACKNOWLEDGE THAT BTR SHALL NOT BE LIABLE FOR CONTENT SUBMITTED BY USERS OF THE BTR WEBSITE OR THE DEFAMATORY, OFFENSIVE, OR ILLEGAL CONDUCT OF ANY THIRD PARTY AND THAT THE RISK OF HARM OR DAMAGE FROM THE FOREGOING AS IT RELATES TO YOUR CONTENT RESTS ENTIRELY WITH YOU.

WITHOUT LIMITING THE FOREGOING PROVISIONS OF THIS SECTION, BTR SHALL HAVE NO LIABILITY FOR ANY LOSSES OR INJURIES, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, TORT, WARRANTY OR OTHERWISE, OR FOR ANY LOST PROFITS OR DIRECT, INDIRECT, SPECIAL, CONSEQUENTIAL OR PUNITIVE DAMAGES RESULTING, IN WHOLE OR IN PART, FROM: 

  1. BTR's actions, omissions or negligence, or for contingencies beyond its control, in procuring, compiling, or delivering the Information, the BTR website or the BTR Services; 
  2. any errors, omissions, or inaccuracies in the Information regardless of how caused, or delays or interruptions in delivery of the Information; 
  3. any decision made or action taken or not taken in reliance upon the Information furnished in connection with the BTR website, whether such Information is posted; 
  4. your use of, or reliance on the Information, or from the use by you of the internet generally; 
  5. your use of, or the inability to use, the BTR Services or the BTR website, even if BTR has been advised of the possibility of such damages; 
  6. any unauthorized access to or use of BTR's servers and/or any and all personal information and/or financial information stored therein; and 
  7. any bugs, viruses, Trojan horses, or the like, which may be transmitted to or through the BTR website by any third party; and
  8. your exposure via the BTR website to programs and other content that are inaccurate, offensive, indecent, or objectionable. 

##### In brief...

We are not liable if something goes really wrong. Always have a backup of your content.

## Online Privacy and Security Statement

### Effective Date: April 22, 2015

BlogTalkRadio Inc. is committed to protecting the privacy of individuals that interact with our websites. This policy discloses the Company's practices governing the gathering and use of information submitted to the Company through [www.blogtalkradio.com](http://www.blogtalkradio.com/) (“Site”) which is owned and operated by BlogTalkRadio Inc. (“BlogTalkRadio”). Any person accessing, browsing, or otherwise using the Site, either manually or via an automated device or program, to the extent permitted hereunder, shall be considered a "User" under this privacy policy. All Users are bound by the terms of this privacy policy. This privacy policy does not apply to the practices of unrelated third-party service providers or companies accessed through links provided for your convenience from this site.

BlogTalkRadio Inc. has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [privacy@BlogTalkRadio.com](mailto:privacy@BlogTalkRadio.com). If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request). The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site: [www.blogtalkradio.com](http://www.blogtalkradio.com/). 

##### 1\. General

BlogTalkRadio respects the privacy of every individual who visits our Web sites, responds to our interactive advertisements or sends us e-mail. This Privacy and Security Statement outlines the information BlogTalkRadio' will collect and how we will use that information. This Statement will also instruct you on what to do if you do not want your personal information collected or shared when you visit BlogTalkRadio' Web sites, respond to our Web-based advertisements or send us email.

##### 2\. Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card number) on our registration or order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). 

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personally identifiable information submitted to us, both during transmission, and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute.

If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can send email us at [privacy@BlogTalkRadio.com](mailto:privacy@BlogTalkRadio.com).

##### 3\. Personally-Identifiable Information

BlogTalkRadio will not collect any personally-identifiable information about you unless you provide it to us voluntarily. Personally-identifiable information includes your name, address, telephone number, credit card information and e-mail address.

The following are some examples of when BlogTalkRadio may require that you provide personally identifiable information:

To register for an account or complete an online order for a service (if you do not wish to complete an online order form, we will always provide an option for you to complete an order by calling a toll free phone number).

To enter an online contest or sweepstakes (if you do not wish to complete an online contest or sweepstakes form, we will always provide an option for you to enter by mailing a 3 x 5 card to a specific address) or to conduct surveys.

To request more information about new or current BlogTalkRadio products or services

If you do not want your personally identifiable information collected, please do not submit it to us. If you have already submitted this information and would like for us to remove it from our records, please contact us at the email address listed at the bottom of this Statement. We will use reasonable efforts to delete your information from our existing files.

When you do provide us with personally identifiable information, we may use that information in the following ways, unless stated otherwise:

We may store and process that information to better understand all customer needs and how we can improve our products and services for all customers.

We may use that information to contact you with new promotions and announcements if you have previously provided your permission and if the promotions and announcements are in your interest.

We may contact you if we have questions about your account.

BlogTalkRadio will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. BlogTalkRadio will not sell, share or rent personally identifiable information to third parties, unless we tell you we are going to do so at the time we collect your personally identifiable information. We are committed to giving you the choice of whether or not we use your information for marketing purposes.

##### 4\. Children

BlogTalkRadio has no intention of collecting any personally-identifiable information from individuals under 18 years of age. Where appropriate, BlogTalkRadio will specifically instruct children not to submit such information on our Web sites or advertisements without consent of a parent or guardian. If a child has provided us with personally-identifiable information without the consent of a parent or guardian, then that child's parent or guardian should contact us at the e-mail address listed at the bottom of this Statement if they would like this information deleted from our records. We will use reasonable efforts to delete the child's information from our existing files.

##### 5\. Non-Personally Identifiable Information

In some cases, we may collect information about you that is not personally identifiable. Examples of this type of information include the type of Internet Browser you are using, the type of computer operating system you are using, and the domain name of the Web site and/or Internet Service Provider from which you linked to our site or advertisement.

Similar to personally-identifiable information, we will not sell non-personally-identifiable information to third parties other than our business partners, unless we tell you we are going to do so at the time we collect the information.

##### 6\. Use of Cookies and other Tracking Technologies

When you view one of our Web sites or advertisements, we may store some information on your computer. This information will be in the form of a "Cookie" or similar file and will be used to determine ways to improve our Web sites, advertisements, products or services. We do link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. For example, Cookies allow us to tailor a Web site to better match your interests and preferences. With most Internet Browsers, you can erase Cookies from your computer hard drive, block all Cookies, or receive a warning before a Cookie is stored. Please refer to your Browser instructions or help screen to learn more about these functions. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site, will be limited.

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by BlogTalkRadio and our partners [specify type e.g. marketing partners], affiliates, or analytics or service providers  [specify type e.g. online customer support provider, etc]. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis. 

The use of cookies by our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company, service providers is not covered by our privacy statement. We do not have access or control over these cookies. Our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company, service providers use session ID cookies, for example, to allow our partners to tailor Advertising to better match your interests and preferences.

##### 7\. Web Beacons

We employ and our third party advertising partner employ a software technology called Web Beacons, that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Web Beacons are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers’ personally identifiable information.

##### 8\. Log Files

As is true of most Web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. 

We use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as Flash to store [content information and preferences.] Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use LSOs such as HTML 5 or Flash to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs. To manage Flash LSOs please click here: <http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html>

##### 9\. Declining E-mail Offers

As outlined in Section 3 of this Statement, we will only send email promotions or announcements to you if you have previously provided your permission for us to do so. Although many customers tell us they appreciate receiving notice of these carefully designed promotions and announcements, we recognize the importance of providing you with choices. At any time, you may remove your name from our e-mail list by contacting us at our e-mail address [privacy@BlogTalkRadio.com](mailto:privacy@BlogTalkRadio.com). All e-mail offers that you receive from BlogTalkRadio will inform you of how to decline receiving further email offers.

##### 10\. Collection of Third Party Information

If you choose to use our referral service to promote your shows via email, we will ask you for your intended recipients name and email address. We will automatically send a one-time email inviting them to listen to your broadcast. BlogTalkRadio stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email

If you choose to request that your show be featured on our site we will ask for the name, phone number, and email address of your guests. BlogTalkRadio stores the information for you to be able to dial your guest and bring them onto a show.

If you wish to no longer have your personal information used by our site, you may request to have it deleted by contacting us at [privacy@BlogTalkRadio.com](mailto:privacy@BlogTalkRadio.com).

##### 11\. Third Party Service Providers

We use other third parties such as a credit card processing company to bill you for goods and services and an email service provider to send out emails on our behalf. We use live chat software to allow you to chat with hosts during their broadcasts. When you sign up for our services, we will share your credit card information with a credit card processing company in order to charge the appropriate fees. We will share your personal information only as necessary for the third party to provide that service.

##### 12\. Surveys and Contests

From time-to-time we may provide you the opportunity to participate in contests or surveys on our site. If you participate, we will request certain personally identifiable information from you. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information such as email address, age and gender, and demographic information (such as zip code).

We use this information to notify contest winners and award prizes,

We may use a third party service provider to conduct these surveys or contests; that company will be prohibited from using our users’ personally identifiable information for any other purpose. We will not share the personally identifiable information you provide through a contest or survey with other third parties unless we give you prior notice and choice.

##### 13\. Legal Disclaimer

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site. We will also share your personal information with any other third party with your prior consent to do so.

If BlogTalkRadio is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.

##### 14\. Who to Contact

If you have submitted personally-identifiable information through a BlogTalkRadio™ Web site or interactive advertisement, and would like that information deleted from our records, please contact us at our e-mail address [privacy@BlogTalkRadio.com.](mailto:privacy@BlogTalkRadio.com) We will use reasonable efforts to delete this information from our existing files and respond to your request within 30 days. We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

##### 15\. Access to Personal Information

If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update or delete your personal information or profile by logging into your account or sending an email to [privacy@BlogTalkRadio.com.](mailto:privacy@BlogTalkRadio.com)

If you wish to update your privacy settings you may do so by logging into your account and accessing your account management page.

If you wish to request the deletion of an unauthorized profile you may do so by emailing [privacy@BlogTalkRadio.com](mailto:privacy@BlogTalkRadio.com).

##### 16\. Social Media Connect and Widgets

You can log in to our site using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect or Gmail log in. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on this Web site to your profile page to share with others within your network.

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

##### 17\. Testimonials

We post customer testimonials on our web site which may contain personally identifiable information. We do obtain the customer's consent via email prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial. If you wish to have your testimonial removed you my contact us at [privacy@BlogTalkRadio.com](mailto:privacy@BlogTalkRadio.com).

##### 18\. Public Forums

Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [privacy@BlogTalkRadio.com](mailto:privacy@BlogTalkRadio.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

##### 19\. Public Directory

If you register as a host, we will list you in our publicly accessible member directory.  If you do not want to be listed in our directory you may choose to register only as a listener, or you may delete your account at any time by contacting us at [privacy@BlogTalkRadio.com](mailto:privacy@BlogTalkRadio.com).

##### 20\. Revisions to this Policy

As the Company grows and new features are added, or legal requirements change, this Privacy Policy may be modified. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices. All information submitted through the Web site is subject to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy, as amended from time to time.

##### 21\. Third Parties

The Site contains links to web sites of third parties. Blogtalkradio is not responsible for the actions of these third parties, including their privacy practices and any content posted on their web sites. We encourage you to review their privacy policies to learn more about what, why and how they collect and use personal information. (Publisher) adheres to industry recognized standards to secure any personal information in our possession, and to secure it from unauthorized access and tampering. However, as is true with all online actions, it is possible that third parties may unlawfully intercept transmissions of personal information, or other users of the Site may misuse or abuse your personal information that they may collect from the Site.

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests.  If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads.  You will continue to receive generic ads.

##### 22\. Contact Us

If you have any questions or concerns regarding this privacy policy your may contact us at privacy@BlogTalkRadio.com or Blogtalkradio Inc. 1072 Madison Ave Lakewood NJ 08701.
